Jhenielle Francis

+44 7585 151122 | jheniellefran@gmail.com Portfolio |GitHub |LinkedIn London, UK, SE10

PROFILE

Applied Data Science and Statistics MSc graduate with a passion for continuous learning, machine learning and building models that translate data into business insights and recommendations. Experience in data querying, data visualization, machine learning, statistical modelling and project and client management. Excellent presentation skills and ability to present technical information to both technical and non-technical audiences.

KEY SKILLS

- R
- Python (Jupyter, NumPy, pandas, Matplotlib, skit-learn)
- SOI
- Machine learning (supervised and unsupervised)
- Data querying with Python and SQL
- Statistical modelling
- Data visualization in R, Python and Tableau

- Probability/Statistics
- Data cleaning
- Data manipulation
- Data wrangling
- Presentation and reporting
- Project management
- Stakeholder management

EDUCATION

MSc in Applied Data Science and Statistics | University of Exeter | Sept 2019 - Sept 2020

- Dissertation Project: Utilising machine learning to investigate electrical activity in ventricular myocytes
- On track for distinction
- Modules included: Applications of Data Science and Statistics, Working with Data, Advanced Topics in Statistics, Advanced Statistical Modelling, Data Governance and Ethics

BA in Psychology | Northwestern University | Sept 2011 - March 2015

Modules included: Introduction to Statistics, Statistical Methods in Psychology, Social Psychology, Chicago Field Studies in Public Health

Associates Degree in Natural Sciences | Hampton High School | Sept 2004-Jun 2011

- 7 CAPEs (A-level equivalent): Grades I-II including Pure Mathematics [II], Communication Studies [II]
- 8 CSECs (GCSE equivalent): Grades I II including English [I], Mathematics [I], Accounting [I]
- Outstanding Performance in CSEC award

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT & TRAINING

Data Science A-Z™: Real-Life Data Science Exercises | Udemy

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate | Coursera | Ongoing

Pathway to Data Analytics | Q-Step Centre

PRINCE2® Foundation in Project Management | AXELOS

PRINCE2® Registered Practitioner in Project Management | AXELOS | Feb 2017 - Feb 2020

CAREER HISTORY

Connector BuddyHub C.I.C.

Dec 2017 - Sept 2019

Award-winning technology start-up combating loneliness and social isolation with a subscription business model

• Onboarded and interviewed all clients (Senior members) and volunteer befrienders (Buddies)

^{*}Grade [I] is the highest grade attainable

- Managed 25 + clients, 50+ volunteers and the relationships between them
- Utilised smart technology and a personalised touch to match clients with their Buddies
- Assisted the CEO in her product owner role, playing a key role in technology platform development
- Carried out key operational and strategic tasks to assist in the company's growth

Intern May 2017 – Dec 2017

BuddyHub C.I.C.

Award-winning tech start-up combating loneliness and social isolation

- Assisted with technology platform development in an agile environment
- Carried out research and operational and strategic tasks to aid in business model development

Freelance Recruiter Nov 2016 - Apr 2017

Self Employed

- Collaborated with hiring managers and management to develop recruitment and staffing strategies
- Pre-screened applications, shortlisted candidates and assisted with interviews
- Supported hiring managers through the interview and selection process

Temporary Administrator Oct 2016
NPW Gifts

Giftware company designing, sourcing and selling products to European and North American retailers

- Provided administrative support to 5 employees to ensure tasks were completed by the set deadlines
- Managed and organised bookings, the company inbox, DPD collections and e-mail archives

Child Care Provider Jan 2016 - Aug 2016
Private family

- Responsible for the safety, well-being and development of three children of ages one, four and seven
- Balanced and re-worked each child's schedule to fit in all activities

Intern Jan 2015 - Mar 2015

The Danny Did Foundation

Non-profit organisation with a mission to increase SUDEP awareness and reduce the risks associated with seizures

- Created, implemented and ran an international educational project, furthering the foundation's brand
- Served as an ambassador at Northwestern University, events and fundraisers

Human Resources Assistant

Summers 2011 - 2013

Mid-Island Corporate Services Limited

Small accounting firm specialising in accounting, business advisory, tax consultation and payroll processing

- Streamlined employee onboarding & training processes
- Assisted with full cycle recruitment and contributed to final hiring decisions

ADDITIONAL IT SKILLS

- MS Office, MS Project, G Suite
- HubSpot CRM, Asana, Trello, Smartsheet
- Google Drive, DropBox, Microsoft OneDrive, Box, SharePoint

References available upon request